KATELYN MICHALOVE

Senior Product Designer

katelynmichalove@gmail.com katelynmichalove.com 615-613-5617

EXPERIENCE

Sunbelt Rentals

Senior Product Designer / May 2021 - Present

- Led a team of junior and mid level designers to completely redesign our eCommerce website.
- Created and presented design process which shifted our team and other teams to be more data driven and hands on when working together to define requirements and features. We gathered analytics, competitive research and launched user surveys and usability testing to guide the creation of our user stories, user flows, wireframes, and final designs including annotations and prototyping for handoff.

Product Designer / Aug 2020 - May 2021

- Created our new onboarding experience for our growing team including one to ones and visits to the field.
- Created personas and user journeys to lead the determination of the feature set required for a B2B mobile application launch.
- Merged previous B2C mobile designs with the authenticated B2B website designs I had led in a previous project to create an omnichannel experience. Created wireframes and final designs with a team of designers.

Junior Product Designer /July 2019 - Aug 2020

- Independently led the redesign of the authenticated space of sunbeltrentals.com and took designs from wireframe to launch.
- As a result of this initiative, time to task for paying invoices decreased by 50% while the amount of invoices paid online increased by 50%.

Procter and Gamble

Process Engineer / Jun 2017 - Jul 2018

 Led troubleshooting for the chemical plant to solve for process improvement areas.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee / 2017 / BA Chemical Engineering

Bloc / 2019 / UX Design Apprenticeship

SUMMARY

I am a Senior Product Designer with skills in conducting user research and leading projects from wireframe to launch. I am datadriven and seek out analytics, user research, and competitive insight to drive design decision. I collaborate with the team to define requirements and develop a product that solves users' problems while meeting business objectives.

TOOLS

Sketch, Figma
Marvel, Invision
Adobe Creative Suite
Dovetail
Lookback
Miro, Figjam
Survey Gizmo/Alchemer
Git, GitHub
Google Analytics
HTML, CSS

SKILL SET

Jira, Confluence

User Experience Design
User Research
Market Research
Usability Testing
Information Architecture
Visual Design
Branding
Prototyping
Frontend Development